nicole duncan

480-490-5198 | | thenicoleduncan@gmail.com | | 1827 E. Lemon St, #16, Tempe, AZ 85281

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-duncan-267489159/ | GitHub: https://github.com/thenicoleduncan | Portfolio: https://thenicoleduncan.github.io/portfolio/

summary

Front End Web Developer and Designer passionate about creating aesthetically pleasing websites to improve user interface experience. Using my newly developed skills to design websites, computer graphic, and social media posts.

technical skills

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, JSX

Applications: MongoDB, Node.js, React.js, Adobe Spark, Microsoft Office

projects

DBYNWTME | | https://mawil583.github.io/Project-1/

- This website allows users to search for the most popular events in a city of their choice. A
 table populates with the event info and the weather information from the exact time
 that the event starts.
- Responsibilities: Front End Developer and Design
- Technical: CSS3, HTML5, Moment.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, Algolia Places Library (autofill), Darksky API, Eventful API, and OpenCage API

In A Giphy | https://thenicoleduncan.github.io/giphy-page/

- A gif finder site that incorporates an ajax call to Giphy's API. This website is designed to display several random gifs associated with the topic of the user's choice.
- Responsibilities: Front End Developer and Design
- Technical: CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap, jQuery, Giphy API

relevant experience

ExitNest | | Front and Back End Web Development Intern

NOVEMBER 2019 - PRESENT, MESA, ARIZONA

Design, create and develop mobile responsive web pages. Primary responsibility is managing the MongoDB database, removing and adding to the collection.

All Around Learning Center | | Social Media and Office Assistant

AUGUST 2019 - PRESENT, MESA, ARIZONA

Create social media posts, schedule and post social media updates, community growth & outreach, reporting on reach, traffic and growth.

Freelance Social Media Manager and Web Designer

OCTOBER 2018 - AUGUST 2019, MESA, ARIZONA

Create social media content, schedule and post social media updates, SEO, frequent use of Adobe Lightroom, community growth & outreach, reporting on reach, traffic and growth. Build and design websites for clients like Elise Glover Photography and MadPics AZ in Mesa, AZ.

education

University of Arizona | | Certificate in Full Stack Development

AUGUST 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020, GILBERT, ARIZONA

Six-month bootcamp where I developed skills such as JavaScript, CSS, React.js, Node.js, and MongoDB. Spent time as project team lead and front end developer.

Mesa Community College | | General Business

AUGUST 2017 - MAY 2019, MESA, ARIZONA

Studied general business courses at Mesa Community College to better understand personal and business management, finances, and professionalism.